

#### **ZONAL MANAGER**

Thonnamattathil Mattakuzhy Varikoly p.o, cochin, 682308, India <a href="mailto:lebinpaulose@gmail.com">lebinpaulose@gmail.com</a> 9074662530,8281283271

# DETAILS

Nationality Indian Date / Place of birth 15/06/1982 KOCHI

# PROFILE

Experienced and self-motivated Sales Manager with 10 years of industry experience overseeing sales figures and new account developments. Bringing forth a proven track record of working collaboratively with sales teams to achieve goals, increase revenue gains, and advance the sales cycle of the company. A strong leader with the ability to increase sales and develop strategies to retain customers.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# ZONAL MANAGER (RETAIL-SALES), CARS24 SERVICES PVT LTD, KOCHI

SEPTEMBER 2021

- Successfully managed a sales team of several people to meet and achieve sales goals.
- Effectively monitored competition and appropriately adjusted costs based on supply and demand.
- Managed sales employees and counseled employees based on their professional growth and productivity.
- Presented sales, revenue, and expenses reports to management teams.

### TEAM LEADER (SALES), PENINSULAR HONDA, Kochi

JULY 2019 - AUGUST 2021

- Monitored the performance of sales team members and worked to increase team morale and motivation.
- Served as a successful leader, promoting and achieving store success.
- Worked well independently and within a team setting.

#### TEAM LEADER (SALES), VOLKSWAGEN COCHIN, Muvattupuzha

JULY 2017 - JULY 2019

- Successfully managed a sales team of several people to meet and achieve sales goals.
- Trained new sales professionals and provided coaching as needed to maintain company sales success.
- Established sales goals by forecasting annual sales quotas and projecting expected sales volume for existing and new products.

## SENIOR SALES CONSULTANT, SAI SERVICE MARUTI SUZUKI, Kochi

JUNE 2016 - JUNE 2017

- Identified and maximized sales opportunities, and increased customer retention rates.
- Trained new sales professionals and provided coaching as needed to maintain company sales success.
- Led sales department with highest quarterly sales for two consecutive years.

# PROJECT LEAD, ACCENTURE INNOVATIONS, TRIPUNITHURA

- Worked closely with project managers and engineers to ensure project needs were fulfilled and budgets were honored.
- Worked to ensure successful project execution according to established objectives, timelines, and costs.
- Worked in collaboration with the senior project manager to define project goals and establish a timeline and plan to achieve them.

## OPERATIONS ASST/ WAREHOUSE MANAGEMENT, WIPRO INFOTECH, COCHIN

APRIL 2009 - JUNE 2013

- Managed other Warehouse Workers and worked with team leaders to enhance productivity.
- Worked productively with Product Team to understand requirements and business specifications around Portfolio Management, Analytics and Risk.

#### SYSTEM ADMIN, DIGITAL SOLUTIONS, COCHIN

OCTOBER 2005 - FEBRUARY 2009

- Scheduled new and follow-up appointments, processed payments and new patient paperwork, and documented all data into the company software system.
- Maintained accurate information in the payroll system.
- Supported an efficient production system in a fast paced environment by accurately processing all new orders, and delegating tasks as each order required.

## ELECTRICIAN TRAINEE, OEN INDIA LIMITED, COCHIN

MARCH 2000 - JULY 2004

- Installed, managed, and maintained energy management systems such as thermostats and digital cycling units.
- Brought forth a hard-work ethic and self-motivated attitude.

## **EDUCATION**

## BA ENGLISH, CMJ University, SIKKIM

JUNE 2010 - MARCH 2013

### HARDWARE AND NETWORKING, ACCEL IT, COCHIN

AUGUST 2004 - AUGUST 2005

# ITI ELECTRICIAL NCVT, ELECTRICIAN, COCHIN

MARCH 1998 - MARCH 2000

# RMHSS VADAVUCODE, SSLC, COCHIN

MARCH 1998

CKILLC

SKILLS	
Time Management	Communication
Fast Learner	Dedicated team player
Highly organized and efficient	Ability to Work Under Pressure
LANGUAGES	
English	Malayalam

# REFERENCES

References available upon request

# COURSES

CCNA

SAP

**ADOBE**